<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>I&mdash;S&mdash;O&mdash;P&mdash;T</title>
 <link href="http://isopt.github.io//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://isopt.github.io//"/>
 <updated>2016-02-21T14:25:01-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://isopt.github.io/</id>
 <author>
   <name>E Roon Kang</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Time as the non-standard measurement</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//2015/08/27/TED-fellows-retreat/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-27T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//2015/08/27/TED-fellows-retreat</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is the script of the talk, presented at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ted.com/21-ted-fellows-share-ideas-that-swim-against-the-tide/&quot;&gt;TED Fellows Retreat 2015&lt;/a&gt;, on Aug 27, 2015, Monterey, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was working on a project in Korea last year, for a public art festival, for which my studio in New York was providing designs. And because of the physical distance between Seoul and New York, we were video conferencing almost every day. These calls had to happen at odd times for everyone – either very early in the morning or very late in the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/talk/E-Roon-Kang-D7.002.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main curators of the event, my friend and collaborator Taeyoon Choi, was also based in New York and was working remotely most of the time. One day, we were complaining about how our professional lives were happening in odd hours while our personal lives were bound to New York’s local time, which made our lives much more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was, as if, we are living in someplace else — in-between New York and Seoul — not completely belonging to either of those places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in our perceptions, those conference calls were happening not in New York or Seoul’s local time, but possibly ‘elsewhen’ — some time else that the participants from both places share momentarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;caption align=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;The First Moving Assembly Line, Highland Park, Michigan, 1913&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/talk/E-Roon-Kang-D7.008.png&quot; alt=&quot;The First Moving Assembly Line, Highland Park, Michigan, 1913&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is based on a movement of planet earth because we consider that as a constant: the speed which the earth rotates around the sun. It’s practical to think of time in this way because it registers every event into a single and linear metric system. It works like an assembly line, our phone calls and email communications, just about anything is bound to this completely linear framework and we rely on this to define “order.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s interesting about this linear narrative is that it has a very definite beginning and end. Time, on a personal level, is unquestionably a finite resource. You can accumulate infinite amount of wealth but you cannot live an infinite life. I think this is the motivation behind every technological advancement. To maximize our use of time by doing more things with less amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, the contemporary world operates in terms of global synchronization. Things happen in real time and this semblance of simultaneity is a defining characteristic of value and a synonym of efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/talk/E-Roon-Kang-D7.012.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as a human being, it’s not uncommon to feel detached from the real time like when you’re jet-lagged and can’t fall asleep or missing your subway stops while daydreaming. These occur when you’re by yourself, not syncing perfectly with the GMT, the Greenwich Mean Time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Taeyoon and I were having conversations like this, we realized that there’s no tool available for us to acknowledge these personal perceptions of different times. These senses are essentially ephemeral, as soon as you look at your watch &lt;em&gt;boom&lt;/em&gt; you’re back in sync with the GMT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to give form to these personal senses of time by conceiving a new measurement system that captures these personal yet ephemeral senses. Then perhaps, we could create a time device that shows your personal time so that you can interact with it without syncing back with the GMT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/talk/E-Roon-Kang-D7.013.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, we could network these devices and think about how to negotiate these personal times from person to person. We could create an alternative time-system, a consensus time, the bottom up approach towards deciding what time it is now as opposed to the top-down approach where we’re basically being told by geo-political standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, we set out to create completely new timezones that are not based on the movement of planet earth but based on your perceptions of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/talk/E-Roon-Kang-D7.014.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past year we have been conspiring on this subject with our latest experiment in Los Angeles about a month ago – which was also the very first time using custom hardware and software we made to capture participants’ personal moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/talk/E-Roon-Kang-D7.016.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a Personal Timekeeper. It’s a simple clock with one button, that displays your Personalized Time. It comes with a little pamphlet describing what is encouraged and discouraged while using them for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We handed out these devices to the participants. Everyone gathered in the same place at the same time, and we instructed them to press and hold the button for a span of time that they thought was a minute, which can be anywhere between 30 sec to 90 seconds. From that point on everyone’s clock would advance in different speeds based on their perceptual minute – either going faster or slower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/talk/cmm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The participants wore the devices and explored the museum. We asked them to come back to the place we started by ‘3:30pm’ which, of course, would now no longer be a single point in time for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the participants were experiencing the detachment from GMT for a few hours, their Personalized Times were shown on a website along with their markings of ‘moments’ – whatever period of time that’s significant to them, which is shown as a timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this subjective history of the participants’ personalized moments we started a roundtable discussion on how we could possibly model a Consensus Time, a shared time space among participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/anycci3nKhY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the current model of GMT, time manifests as a uniform backbone to everything that happens. It’s the ultimate unit of measurement that everyone has to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/talk/E-Roon-Kang-D7.022.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe we can take back our ownership of our sense of time, as opposed to giving in to the conforming standards of time. We can create an alternate logic for keeping track of time. Perhaps we selectively synchronize our Personalized Times with a small number of people – friends, families or co-workers – from time to time, then drift away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea of not conforming to the standardized time might seem a little far-fetched but I believe it’s a step towards acknowledging and respecting the vastly different and beautiful ways of how we all navigate through this complicated world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Personal Timekeeper and Circle of Moment Measurement</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//2015/07/21/CircleofMoment/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-21T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//2015/07/21/CircleofMoment</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past few months, E Roon and I worked on The Personal Timekeeper v.1, an electronic device that gives form to the user’s personal sense of time. We designed and fabricated a custom hardware and software system for a participatory performance and workshop at Los Angeles County Museum of Art (LACMA) held on 7/18~19 2015 titled Circle of Moment Measurement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5711/20510940472_346c61ce83.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to our previous workshops and time based experiments such as &lt;a href=&quot;2014/09/13/TimekeeperInventionClubReport/&quot;&gt;Timekeeper Invention Club&lt;/a&gt;, we hoped to create a situation for uncommon discussions of time by facilitating a temporary gathering of individuals with different perspectives about human agency on time. The idea was to create a roundtable among ‘time travellers’, a cliche term in popular culture which we appropriated to mean people literally travelling in different speeds and points in time. We thought the best way to realize this would be to create an experience for them to visualize differences in their perception of time, give them agency to control time through tactile control then bring them together to discuss their  differences in their perception of time. This exercise of measuring ‘moments’, an abstract term to give form to the semantics of time, would culminate in ‘circle’ like a close-knit tribal community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-timekeeper-v1&quot;&gt;Personal Timekeeper v.1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Personal Timekeeper is designed to enable experiencing time differently, more subjectively and personally. Technically, it’s a wooden box with a button, numeric display, power supply and a custom board connecting the components to a small computer (Raspberry Pi) communicating to the Internet via cellular signal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5637/20331698940_7ff049e618.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Personal Timekeeper is initialized by the user by pressing down the button for how long they think a minute feels like. After releasing the button, the Personal Timekeeper proceeds ‘keeping’ time on the speed based on your perceptual minute — If your perceptual minute was 30 seconds, your 1 minute is going to be very fast (30 seconds in Universal Time). Your time is constantly broadcasted on the Circle for Moment Measurement &lt;a href=&quot;http://moment.isopt.info/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; under a custom URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5756/20519806155_5bc1139b72.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This image shows that Kyle McDonald initialized his time on 2:46 pm on 7/18/2015 Pacific Time, he’s currently living in 7:27 pm on 7/20/2015 but as it’s actually 8:58 pm on 7/21/2015 Pacific Time. We can understand that his personal time is slower than the Standard Time because his initialization was longer than 60 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second feature is holding down the button to mark a moment. The moment is defined by whatever period of time that’s significant to you. Each moment can also hold different meanings. We intended to avoid any meta data about the user (such as heart beat, location) or extra media such as photo or video about the moment. The moment is just time in its elements. The information about the moments are saved in the server and visualized as dots and lines on the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5756/20519806155_5bc1139b72.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this picture, you can see the times and durations when I pressed the button over the course of few days. These are the markings of moment in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also trigger prompts (instructions and suggestions) to spend your time. When the Personal Timekeepers are triggered by a quick tap on the button, a random choice of prompts including the following are assigned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change something small in the space that you are in right now, like moving a pebble on the curb. Think about everything that might have changed due to your action.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch other museum visitors walk by and observe for five minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try to fall in love with someone as fast as you can.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask a museum visitor “What time is it, where you came from?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The participants are asked not to verbally engage with other participants unless both parties agree to speak by circling around each other. The museum guards were informed about the performance and there were signs around the museum about it to inform the visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;circle-of-moment-measurement&quot;&gt;Circle of Moment Measurement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Circle of Moment Measurement workshop was organized in the following steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5735/20519339725_b12c8f81a3.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1pm Participants come in. Registration on moment.isopt.info to make their account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5834/20510682792_640aa905f4.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1:15 Begin presentation for the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5833/19898434793_ee784a6097.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2:15 Participants sign in at the Museum entrance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5705/19898436453_dcf252f828.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5645/20331312318_138bfbfb3c.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5681/20525701461_c12ae6342c.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2:30 Participants initialize their moments with the Personal Timekeepers at the BP Grand Entrance in the first day and LA Times Court in the second day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5833/20331245080_68a1090c2e.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5684/19896686114_9acaf75787.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;2:30~3:30 Performance. Participants explored the spaces and time in the museum.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;3:30 PRST (Personalized time) Participants meet back in the Lab. Since their times are different, they arrive in different times.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5628/20332641949_f27ae8fee0.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;~4:00 Participants recorded short videos about their moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5687/20510538112_011906f086.jpg =500x&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4~5pm Roundtable discussion about Consensus Time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final stage of the workshop, the participants joined a roundtable about their Consensus Time. In preparation for the workshop, we designed an online system to calculate and display the consensus time. We hoped to arrive at some kind of consensus among the participants about the shared time and broadcast the consensus time on the dedicated page as well as one of the Personal Timekeepers to be displayed in LACMA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5776/20493557966_822e2c2b2e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation renewed our interest about the multiplicities of times. After about an hour of conversation we didn’t get to reach the consensus. Maybe that’s rather revealing about the nature of consensus. However, on the process we agreed to live in this moment and to reflect that we have already made a consensus to be present here and now. It may have been an unachievable question to begin with. After all, similarly to the ‘moment’, an intentionally obscure term that may mean anything, ‘consensus’ was intentionally designed to provoke conversation. On the first day, we agreed that we can’t reach a consensus and the on the second day we created a list on guidance for the consensus which every participant contributed one statement. Everyone got three stickers to pick their choice, an exercise in primitive democracies of time. We returned to our initial curiosity. If everyone’s time is different, can we create a bottom up approach to determining time, and what would be the democracy of time? We still don’t have answers to it, we just have few more leads since the time we started our project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/YF_W7o2YfyA
&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To watch the longer edit, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=anycci3nKhY&quot;&gt;this version&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/80913365@N04/sets/72157657091546896&quot;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt;. Also check out an article by Amy Heibel on LACMA’s blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://unframed.lacma.org/2015/08/12/artists-choi-and-kang-bend-time-lacma&quot;&gt;Unframed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Joel Ferree and Amy Heibel of LACMA. Jon Moeller, Charlotte Stiltes, Wonyoung So, Kurt Keppeler for video and Drunkin for photographs. Also big thanks to all of the workshop participants.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Circle of Moment Measurement: 7/18 – 19</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//2015/06/20/CircleofMomentMeasurement/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-20T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//2015/06/20/CircleofMomentMeasurement</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What is time really?  As humanity, we collectively agree on using Universal Time as a standard to keep things in order in an increasingly synchronized and complex society. However, is it the only way to measure your time on this earth? What if we re-design time based off of your perception of moments?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By being part of the Circle of Moment Measurement, you will collectively agree to all live by different times. Everyone in this participatory performance will discover their own personalized speed of time that is kept in portable and networked timekeeping devices, designed by the artists with support of LACMA Art + Technology Lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this participatory performance, there will be a chance to experience the public spaces in LACMA in your own time. After that a conversation about how the new forms of time measurement would affect life would follow, as well as a opportunity to share the experience with the world.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a half-day event, led by the artists, requires about a four-hour time commitment. The afternoon concludes with video interviews documenting the experience and a group discussion about how alternative time measurement might affect daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Circle of Moment Measurement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;7/18-19, 2015, 1–5pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
LACMA, Art + Technology Lab&lt;br /&gt;
Art of the Americas Building&lt;br /&gt;
5905 Wilshire Boulevard, Los Angeles, CA 90036&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7/18&lt;/strong&gt; – PRIVATE BETA&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;1pm – 5 pm&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first event is a private, invitation-only event for artists’ collaborators and the community around the Art + Technology Lab. Request for an invitation &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/10Lb_mrQpcvbrb3-MKxXuDQlLJY5j0MzOw2qxfhlX87E&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7/19&lt;/strong&gt; – OPEN TO PUBLIC&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;1pm – 5pm&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The public event Circle of Moment Measurement is the final component of &lt;em&gt;In Search of Personalized Time&lt;/em&gt;. More information and sign up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lacma.org/event/artist-workshop&quot;&gt;LACMA’s event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Timekeeper Invention Club Report</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//2014/09/13/TimekeeperInventionClubReport/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-13T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//2014/09/13/TimekeeperInventionClubReport</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Timekeeper Invention Club is an occasional workshop that explores the meaning of ‘personalized time.’ As part of the 2014 LACMA Art + Technology Lab commission &lt;em&gt;In Search of Personalized Time (I—S—O—P—T)&lt;/em&gt;, the Club contributes to the research and public engagement goals &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taeyoon Choi and E Roon Kang held a Timekeeper Invention Club Workshop in Art + Technology Lab at LACMA on August 30th, 2014. The workshop began with presentations by the artists about their previous projects as well as the impetus for collaborating on &lt;em&gt;I—S—O—P—T&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3888/14946777298_a9116bea7b_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E Roon talked about some of his personal works, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://eroonkang.com/projects/manual-the-manual/&quot;&gt;Manual:The Manual&lt;/a&gt;(2009), &lt;a href=&quot;http://eroonkang.com/projects/study-additive-white/&quot;&gt;Additive White&lt;/a&gt;(2008), sharing his sardonic thoughts on the overly calculated, complicated society. With the projects such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://eroonkang.com/projects/trash-track/&quot;&gt;Trash Track&lt;/a&gt;(2010), a project at MIT SENSEable City Lab, he pointed out that the socially shared expectation of efficiency often leads to the abject pointlessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taeyoon talked about the sense of displacement that comes with periods of of jet lag. His talk took inspiration from a quote by South Korean artist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.heikejung.de/list_of_works.html&quot;&gt;Haegue Yang&lt;/a&gt;: “Jet lag describes the site of love as time in which one is alone, e.g. awake alone in the night, socially less compatible and in this time-space of aloneness one can love and be loved without a division of self and the other.” (Max Andrews, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lttds.org/assets/Andrews-HaegueYang-ENGL.pdf&quot;&gt; Towards Hague Yang’s Blind Rooms&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taeyoon showed some drawings inspired by being ‘on time’ and ‘out of time.’ Interested in how time can be treated as a malleable object, Taeyoon also showed &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/tchoi8/timekeeper-invention-club&quot;&gt;timekeeping hardware&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoonchoi.com/2013/04/storage-to-memory/&quot;&gt;storege devices&lt;/a&gt; for digital and analog memory that he’s currently working on.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5583/15132949902_3f3c1a1881_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E Roon and Taeyoon also talked about the current state of &lt;em&gt;I—S—O—P—T&lt;/em&gt;, their unique research method through experimental events such as Real-Time Film Club and plans for making series of prototypes inspired by critical theory, design and technology. They touched on the variety of ideas orbiting the project, including simultaneity, synchronization, standardization, memory, action, and how to give form to intangible experiences, ideas, and sensations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3845/14946774938_e8d1152aa3_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a brief break, the artists introduced the &lt;em&gt;Timekeeper Invention Kit&lt;/em&gt;: a complete package of tools and materials for workshop participants to make their own timekeeper, or ‘personal time machine.’ In the Kit, there were handmade objects: such as a smartphone crafted out of balsa, and electronics such as LEDs, a motor, a paper circuit, as well as variety of construction and drawing material. Everyone received a paper box, vaguely resembling a box for smart phones or jewelry, which prompts users to create a timekeeper that gives form to their personal sense of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3871/15133336675_113dc73734_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3884/14946674170_4262b82456_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before building, there was a collective brainstorming among the participants. Using terms and themes that were introduced earlier as anchors, the participants mapped out their thoughts and anecdotes on the wall of the Lab. Then the participants focused on making their own timekeeper, with conceptual and material assistance from the artists. Some of the participants made their timekeeper collaboratively.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3848/15133336105_e756a2ee14_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the workshop’s final phase, participants demonstrated their timekeeper’s functionality and story in front on video for 1 minute. There was a wide range of outcomes. Jake, a young boy, in collaboration with his father Tom Putnam, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JwSVnsNdwWw&quot;&gt;made a watch&lt;/a&gt; that could control the speed of time passing with a knob. The dial reads from “1 to 14th” hour and it’s minute hand and hour hand are glued together, such that the hands are always 90 degrees apart. In the video, he demonstrates spinning the clock hands and guessing where it has landed, simialar to the Wheel of Fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Istrin made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KWhb1elqhFA&quot;&gt;a box to count her age&lt;/a&gt;, with long wooden sticks standing for a decade and short sticks standing for a year. On her 60th birthday, she will take out 9 short sticks from the box and replace them with a long stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julianne Lee and Maxwell Williams collaborated on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hUag8vrAjvM&quot;&gt;Limited Edition Infinity&lt;/a&gt;, an electronic circuit with a dozen of LEDs arranged in shape of infinity sign, connected parallel to a 3 Volt battery. The catch is the battery has been soldered to the circuit, so their ‘infinity’ will last only as long as the energy remains in this one specific battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3887/14946633439_109822ca6a_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous weekend, E Roon and Taeyoon hosted the same workshop at &lt;a href=&quot;http://orbitalnyc.com/&quot;&gt;Orbital&lt;/a&gt;, a creative coworking space in New York City. Friends and acquaintances participated to make their own timekeepers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRJ-zU7EPMM&amp;amp;list=PLXfQk5ShZ9LZzlrO3N35vJfepFlyB52Pp&amp;amp;index=14&quot;&gt;Ishac Bertran&lt;/a&gt; created a binary clock based on the concept of flip flops (simplest digital circuit with two stable states that can store information) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RN5kxRrqOiU&amp;amp;index=16&amp;amp;list=PLXfQk5ShZ9LZzlrO3N35vJfepFlyB52Pp&quot;&gt;Ellie Irons&lt;/a&gt; created multidimensional timekeeper based on phenology and the academic calendar year. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ln4e6Fe9oQE&amp;amp;list=PLXfQk5ShZ9LZzlrO3N35vJfepFlyB52Pp&amp;amp;index=12&quot;&gt;Lauren McCarthy&lt;/a&gt; animated a story about lovers frustration with different sense of time, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PPlDSJ-7gLA&amp;amp;list=PLXfQk5ShZ9LZzlrO3N35vJfepFlyB52Pp&amp;amp;index=10&quot;&gt;Dan Phiffer&lt;/a&gt; talked about different ways to avoid indication of time on a smart phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3870/14947474808_52d76f3aec_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3873/15134029375_298d9391c6_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5587/14947470218_6a70a44abc_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this collaborative thought exercise, Taeyoon and E Roon are trying to provide an opportunity to rethink about time and to give form to everyday perceptions of it. Some aspects of the kits and workshop are rooted in their reflection of contemporary obsession in ‘personalization’ of digital devices, as well as in technology’s mediation of communication and senses of ‘presentness.’ By making conceptual timekeepers with common materials, the workshop encourages everyone to craft their own sense of time.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/KWhb1elqhFA?list=PLXfQk5ShZ9LZzlrO3N35vJfepFlyB52Pp&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The artists are planning to a third incarnation of Timekeeper Invention Club at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dxboston.com/session/timekeeper-invention-club/&quot;&gt;Design Exchange Boston&lt;/a&gt; on 9.28.2014 and continue to explore personal sense of time and archive short videos of other people’s inventions on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLXfQk5ShZ9LZzlrO3N35vJfepFlyB52Pp&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I—S—O—P—T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timeline of the workshop at Art + Technology Lab, LACMA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12:45 First guest &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1:00 Official beginning of the workshop &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1:15 Workshop begins/ Introduction to the project/ Participants say Hello&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1:30 Roon presentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2:00 Taeyoon presentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2:30 break&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2:45 Timekeeper Invention Tool Kit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3:00 Collective brainstorming &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3:30 Individual project &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4:00 First project documentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:30 Final project documentation &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Real-Time Film Club Report</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/29/Realtimefilmclub-report/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-29T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/29/Realtimefilmclub-report</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past Saturday, Roon and Taeyoon held the first meeting of the Real Time Film Club. I unfortunately could not attend — I was hosting an out-of-town friend, and my schedule was subject to his jetlag. But this morning we met and they recounted the evening to me, and it sounded like a great time. They are happy with how it went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3904/14357341248_c52f850f14_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time around, we wanted a small group of peers to discuss these themes, and there was a great crop of precisely that. There was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deepspeedmedia.com/&quot;&gt;Jonathan Minard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thelisapark.com/#/&quot;&gt;Lisa Park&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.woebken.net/&quot;&gt;Chris Woebken&lt;/a&gt;, among others. Everyone gathered in a circle on the floor, with snacks, next to two projection surfaces that we had set up on the ground. One screen projected the movie Time Code, and the other projected an actual time code in real time. The plan was that the event’s pacing would be dictated by the film’s passing: it would last as long as  the movie’s duration. The goal was to conduct &lt;strong&gt;“an exercise in simultaneity”&lt;/strong&gt;: people in space together, synching up for a brief time, and becoming aware of the time they are passing together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5592/14357313829_e5ddd96a6c_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taeyoon and Roon tell me that one of the biggest surprises was that Time Code was actually enjoyable to watch. We were all worried that it would appear cheesy, but after all our hand-wringing, it sounds like the framing saved the day. The installation, and the way that Taeyoon and Roon decided to introduce it, emphasized the structure of the film over its plot, and that provided a kind of schematic for everyone to think about and work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone ate food and watched the first half hour of the movie as the timecode projection tracked their progress. One thing that struck the group was how its ambitions are impossible for one person to fully apprehend: it makes you want to see everything when you definitely never can. In talking about it after, everyone filled in each other’s missing pieces, and they built a shared understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2929/14542387264_df0c1b33cb_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the screening, everyone hung around for another hour and a half and talked about how these themes fit into their own lives. There was a lot of discussion of real time technology (social media) and the kinds of relationships that it makes possible. What does Gchat enable, and what does a letter enable? How are they different? Does Skype always make you feel closer to a person, or can it sometimes actually emphasize the distance between you? As is so often the case with conversations, this one took a few unexpected and exciting turns. Surveillance was one rather surprising topic — or, more specifically, how surveillance technologies and intimate communications are far closer to one another than we might actually be comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2938/14357337058_307cdb7e10_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documentary filmmaker Jonathan’s work brought these questions to challenging territory. He keeps a practice of documenting his own life with a GoPro camera. Halfway through the evening, he showed the footage that he had taken as everyone was arriving. Taeyoon said he felt kind of uncomfortable seeing himself walking up the stairs, just half an hour before, from someone else’s viewpoint. This was one illustration of the kind of “fractured experience” that was a recurring thread throughout the night. He wondered if that kind of footage should exist, but then Roon pointed out how that kind of footage is a cornerstone for how we will remember that evening ten years from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5521/14542384274_001dd8729d_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These kinds of tangents are exactly why these kinds of events happen — Taeyoon and Roon hope to enrich the fabric of the project with the ideas and experiences of their peers and collaborators. From what they tell me, this meeting was a very promising start. We’re already talking about how to adapt the formula for the next meetings, and see what kinds of gatherings we can formulate next.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Real-Time Film Club</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/27/Realtimefilmclub/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-27T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/27/Realtimefilmclub</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Real-Time Film Club is a casual, sporadically held series of meet-ups meant to generate in-depth discussions around I-S-O-P-T with likeminded artists, scientists, and thinkers. At Real-Time Film Club, a screening may or may not involve watching films that present themselves as “real-time” (think Run Lola Run), and it may or may not involve mechanisms for playing with the film’s temporality. The name itself is intentionally a bit mysterious and maybe even misleading, and we hope that the screenings follow in a similarly contingent spirit.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first event, we will be screening director Mike Figgis’s 2000 film Time Code. We are interested in the premise of the film, its technique as material, rather than its cinematic quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You are looking at a movie screen split into four parts. You will see a tale of sex and power, captured by four different cameras. You will witness a story told in real time, without any edits. You will experience the first movie ever told in four dimensions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xqeIYgFqYGw&quot;&gt;Click here for the trailer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3849/14543985475_355c375435_o.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real-Time Film Club meetings rely on the finite, linear temporality of specific media— such as a film or a televised sports event — and take advantage of it to explore the different feelings of temporality that can arise from a social gathering in physical space. In the first installment of Real-time Film Club, we will experiment with what exactly this could mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cinema, as we all know, is a time-based medium. But cinematic time has its own character, which is always in tension with lived experience. A film will condense a day into ninety minutes; a lifetime into two hours. We’re interested in the awkward mixing and slippage of viewing time, narrative time, and filming time as a way of sparking discussions of the differences between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s this tension that has produced the novelty phenomenon of “real-time” films: movies that promise to give us “real” time — by this they usually mean uninterrupted linear time (think Run Lola Run, or 24).  We want to challenge the idea that this time is exclusively “real.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our first experiment, we are screening a film titled Time Code. Its selection  was almost accidental — we looked through a list of films that try to depict “real-time” and picked one that seemed particularly peculiar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And peculiar it is. It turns out that it has incredibly mixed reviews. But rather than evaluate this one for its cinematic value and narrative, we are interested in what the film dreams of — what it aspires to — rather than how it fails. In Time Code, we are given four movie-length film takes following different actors — no cuts — displayed side by side simultaneously. While its story is forgettable, we are interested in its method, its mechanisms, and its desirability: what made this kind of “real-time” monitoring, simultaneity, synchrony, so appealing, at least for the director fifteen years ago? and what values does that reflect in society more generally then and now? What can it tell us about popular perceptions of time today, and where does it fall short?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope to answer those questions together. Ultimately, what we want from Real-Time Film Club is to create a platform for collectively engaging different senses of time. Film is a good prompt for this, simply by having a special ability to pull us out of real time and put us into a different sense of it. It’s also just nice to watch movies together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens at future Real Time Film Club meetings will vary from one event to the next. The only commonality is that it makes use of real-time media (in its broadest sense, ranging from real-time broadcast soccer matches to ‘real-time’ films like Time Code).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://orbitalnyc.com/&quot;&gt;Orbital&lt;/a&gt; for hosting us.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Call with Chris Malachowsky</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/20/chris/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-20T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/20/chris</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a video call with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Malachowsky&quot;&gt;Chris Malachowsky&lt;/a&gt;, the co-founder of NVIDIA who also serves as an advisor for Art + Technology Lab program at LACMA.  Here’s part of the message I sent him a few days before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We’re interested in creating alternative methods of giving form to time. The idea is to stage a network of clocks (with distributed users behind them) that can synchronize and desynchronize with one another, collectively determining the temporal status of both each part and the whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In our thinking behind the project, we see a resonance with parallel computing. For my part, I am engaging these ideas through using &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fpga&quot;&gt;FPGA&lt;/a&gt; and low-level electronics to build prototypes for simple parallel processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In order to further this exploration, I would like to learn more about the research that is done at NVIDIA, by engaging in conversation with engineers about ways of simulating large-scale parallel systems for alternative methods of timekeeping. I am also interested in using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.nvidia.com/cuda#axzz35UrmuRuS&quot;&gt;CUDA platform&lt;/a&gt;, Tesla and GPU hardware in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Technical R&amp;amp;D and philosophical investigation are equally important parts of our commission. Being an artist, I feel more at home creating meaning with technology and experimenting with it — I feel less at home with systematic technical research and implementation. For this reason, I am interested in talking with your specialists and learning from their expertise”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Amy and Joel, the call was scheduled only a week after the initial email. I felt a bit anxious. I didn’t feel ready to talk about the project, because he’s an expert electrical engineer and I have not yet done extensive research on the theory and practice of parallel and GPU programming. I soon realized that there is no real reason to worry about asking basic questions, and that as an artist I have a good excuse to ask the most fundamental questions of all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to think about the reasons behind my interest in parallel computing and how the philosophy relates to technology, some of whi are kept on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://taeyoon-debug.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;debugview&lt;/a&gt; blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I downloaded CUDA platform and built some sample codes. The first one was Mandelbot which could be generated from GPU and CPU. It was clear to see the difference in frames per second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/cuda.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At about 2PM we got on the call. He was in his home office near San Jose and we were in Orbital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about the original proposal for the project. It is pleasantly surprising that many of the A+T advisors read our proposal so carefully and provided personal comment. Chris is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also talked about our initial visit to LACMA last month. While Chris was the one who suggested meet-ups of the artists and the advisors, he unfortunately wasn’t able to join in person. I tried to fill him in about how other grant recipients are taking the advisory relationship to a variety of ways — for example, Rachel is doing a residency at JPL. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After twenty minutes of exciting convresation, we decided it would be beneficial to visit NVIDIA’s research facility in San Jose sometime during the project. Chris was also generous to provide advice and support for the project. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step will be to identify what we would like to achieve with this hardware and software environment, as I am still researching technical possibilities and we have not begun designing the project’s manifestation. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Uneven Measures</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/13/uneven-measures/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-13T08:15:24-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/13/uneven-measures</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In early 2000s, a close friend of mine was running a design studio in Shanghai, China, and I visited him one summer for a few days. The following is a story my friend told me over drinks, recounted as clearly as I remember it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His studio had been working on a national advertising campaign for a clothing label for several years. Part of his responsibility was to design, print and ship big banners to cover the facades of over a hundred department stores all over the country. It was a time-consuming job—it took a lot of small tweaks to make the banner fit to each facade perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, he would complete and ship designs (shipping could take weeks due to inconsistent road conditions). And like clockwork he would get a call from the store manager, telling him that the banners didn’t fit. This happened far too frequently, these logistics were taking too much of his studio’s time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend still didn’t have a clue why the measurements didn’t match. A couple of years before, he had asked every department store to remeasure their frames, but the numbers were always inconsistent. So he and his client initiated a new project last year: they hired a person to visit every department store in the country and get the correct facade measurements. It would take months to visit them all, but their hope was to solve the problem once and for all and finally figure out why this had happened in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;caption align=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;Expressways of China&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/56/Map_of_NTHS_Expressways_of_China.png/1256px-Map_of_NTHS_Expressways_of_China.png&quot; alt=&quot;Expressways of China&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The measurement specialist had returned a few weeks before my visit. His findings about the situation was rather significant: it turned out that the tape measures were inconsistent from town to town, and brand to brand! There were other reasons too, but if your tape measures are unreliable, the other reasons don’t really matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so struck by that story. It felt like a flash of harsh reality found in a small crevice of the ever-so-smoothly presented world, where we conveniently believe in the reliability of standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the trip, I came back to US and went to Home Depot one day. Remembering the story, I got three different tape measures off the rack. They came from all over the world. I pulled all of them out to their maximum length—something like 30 feet—only to find that they too, differ slightly in measurement. Even though the difference was small, I had to wonder how the 1700-feet-tall Freedom Tower can stand, and how hundreds of airplanes land safely every day. It left me feeling a little uncomfortable, doubting that there’s anything absolutely concrete in the  world. In the end, everything is an approximation of everything – but that is also, somehow, very comforting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Route_inspection_problem&quot;&gt;Chinese Postman Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coastline_paradox&quot;&gt;Coastline Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>To give form</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/06/to-give-form/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-06T08:15:24-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//2014/06/06/to-give-form</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quantification is at the heart of modern societies on all levels – from GDP and census to personal bank accounts, Dropbox, and Gmail. Everything is constantly changing and we measure each change in various ways in order to feel in control. If there’s one thing that doesn’t change, it is the speed of time passing. Since it is a rare (if not only) constant in our life, time became the indispensable central unit of all kind of measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminds me of the garment conveyors that we see in every laundromat. As soon as I hook a cloth on, it slowly and apathetically moves my garment towards the back of the room, no matter what type or color the garment is. Whenever I see a clock, or when I sync my Gmail inbox, I feel like I’m hooking myself onto this giant conveyor, moving at a constant speed, where everything is flattened into a single strand of continuous movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/img/Standard_Garment_Conveyor.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my perception of time isn’t constant or continuous. It is fragmentary, organic, and most of all, malleable. When I daydream on a train, it might only “last” a second, but the train of thought travels further, and time dilates. It seems as if time stands still in the middle of a boring lecture, but it can’t move slowly enough when lying down on a Mediterranean beach. This subjective perception of time is dependent on personal experiences, emotions, and memory. It is primarily based on bodily senses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not know how to gauge these senses. Since these perceptions are not easily quantifiable, they are undervalued. They hold little to no value in modern life. I need to be back at work punctually, and the fact that my Mediterranean vacation is passing too quickly is no excuse to return late.  In a society based on uniform Newtonian time, unstandardized personal time is easily ignored, for the sake of mass efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These bodily senses need adequate representation in life. Finding ways to measure these senses is to acknowledge their existence and to find vocabularies to communicate them. And perhaps by sharing these senses, we can also imagine an alternative framework of time, based on bottom-up consensus of personal times. To give form is &lt;em&gt;“to become a gaze that won’t be forgotten.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Flower&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Before I called her name,&lt;br /&gt;
she was nothing&lt;br /&gt;
more than a gesture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I called her name,&lt;br /&gt;
she came to me&lt;br /&gt;
and became a flower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As I called her name,&lt;br /&gt;
will someone please call my name&lt;br /&gt;
that suits my light and fragrance?&lt;br /&gt;
I, too, long to come to her&lt;br /&gt;
and become her flower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We all long to be something.&lt;br /&gt;
You to me, and I, to you,&lt;br /&gt;
long to become a gaze that won’t be forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;— by &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Chunsu&quot;&gt;Kim Chun-soo&lt;/a&gt; (1922-2004)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LA Trip</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//meeting/2014/05/28/LAtrip/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-28T08:15:24-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//meeting/2014/05/28/LAtrip</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We went to LA for our first visit to LACMA Art + Technology Lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3843/14375206211_1a39ca9834_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3880/14353046714_5467d28444_c.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking out the plane’s window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5588/14167455528_b33b969baa.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to see the world’s tallest building in the making at the Gensler officer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3847/14374270933_118a060f85_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical day at Art + Technology Lab at LACMA, meeting with advisors and curators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3838/14374271793_9ca9f7dcb5_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also went to JPL’s facility and saw Mars Rover in action on earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3853/14192107737_70de1b123a_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5522/14352530012_768b417796_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2936/14350767571_6f64b26b56_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More on our trip on LACMA &lt;a href=&quot;http://lacma.wordpress.com/2014/05/22/art-technology-lab-artists-visit-l-a/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2904/14378547455_30b7010c9a_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2938/14350769031_5a977eed2b_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>glossary</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//reading/2014/04/24/words/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-24T08:20:24-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//reading/2014/04/24/words</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We ordered some books that are related to the project. We plan to take notes and share thoughts on time and technology over the next few months. We are especially interested in French philosophers such as Bernard Stiegler and Gilbert Simondon as well as non-academic thinkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few weeks, E Roon and I have been working with Nick Irvin, our research assistant for the project, on rewriting our project description and conceptualizing the direction of the project. Thanks to Nick, we have been able to make visibile progress. After many revisions, we collected a glossary of words and phrases to define some ambigious points in project description. Making the list of terms also provided an opportunity to engage in conversations about the project from different perspectives. Below is a preliminary list of glossary. To view our live working document of the full list, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackpad.com/Elsewhen-Glossary-oHUuh0aIktI&quot;&gt;this hackpad.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7309/13977819079_c15a2ab5cb_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-form-and-to-name&quot;&gt;To form and to name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give form to unformed object, concept, thought&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability and potential to give form to such things or ideas  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naming, enumerating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;simultaneity&quot;&gt;Simultaneity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simultaneity is distinct from synchronization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Concept of Now&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Value of simultaneity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sleep or downtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;inventory-of-times&quot;&gt;Inventory of times&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Absolute time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Standardized time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Synchronized time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desynchronized time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personalized time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consensus time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Real time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Un-real time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presence&quot;&gt;Presence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Present&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flexibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plasticitiy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multitude&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collective&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Individuation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sense-of-place&quot;&gt;Sense of place&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compression&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;space of flows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Postmodern space&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyday and everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Habit and habitat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5518/13977738959_546c767823_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roon drawing time and space coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2902/13977746857_f0bdc050b9_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7384/13977756080_acb3191aaa_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me with glossary on whiteboard. The board says Kickstarter because we are working in part at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orbitalnyc.com/&quot;&gt;Orbital on 155 Rivington street&lt;/a&gt;, which used to be Kickstarter HQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7325/14161078531_f0e98d4745_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick taking picture of this drawing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7104/14025328905_38fbfd997f_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jet lag describes the site of love as time in which one is alone, e.g. awake alone in the night, socially less compatible and in this time-space of aloneness one can love and be loved without a division of self and the other.” From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lttds.org/assets/Andrews-HaegueYang-ENGL.pdf&quot;&gt;“Towards Haegue Yang’s Blind Rooms”&lt;/a&gt; by Max Andrews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7273/14002208786_d3f1732cf0_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventory of times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2915/14002208966_375aeeabd7_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coordinates, symbols and metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First reading list</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//reading/2014/04/24/First-reading-list/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-24T08:15:24-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//reading/2014/04/24/First-reading-list</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We ordered some books that are related to the project. We plan to take notes and share thoughts on time and technology over the next few months. We are especially interested in French philosophers such as Bernard Stiegler and Gilbert Simondon as well as non-academic thinkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5271/14024728195_9822de79cc_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes from Heidegger’s &lt;em&gt;Being and Time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2897/14001686426_3b9018b513_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2927/14024821635_161052fa76_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5510/14024803415_ffe20b8b13_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes from Stiegler’s &lt;em&gt;What Makes Life Worth Living?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7431/14025321884_d5884afb4c_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5084/14025321694_974ca973b5_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we read, we are trying to keep notes of our thoughts and conversations. We will be sharing these as we go on and we hope to aggregate in some kind of publication later on. Nick and I are reading Stiegler’s &lt;em&gt;Technics and Time 1&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the updates and feel free to contact us if you’d like to share thoughts on the readings.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Meeting note, 4/21</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//meeting/2014/04/21/meeting-notes/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-21T12:15:24-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//meeting/2014/04/21/meeting-notes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;E Roon, Nick and I met on 4/21 3~6pm in 155 Rivington street, New York City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5467/14021154681_43b8ce7c0d_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2930/14044345473_22f739f365_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2896/14044344503_32258634dd_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More pictures are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/80913365@N04/sets/ 72157644382832403&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2912/14001047196_81550c0379_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This photo’s from a different but related meeting, where we were prototyping icons for the project. This photograph This photograph is inspired by Tamagochi-like games where players trade virtual items in real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5479/14149025146_6d0b513b17_o.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LACMA Art + Technology Lab announced 5 grant recipients</title>
   <link href="http://isopt.github.io//meeting/2014/04/09/LACMA-Art-Technology-Lab-annouced-5-grant-recipients/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-09T12:15:24-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://isopt.github.io//meeting/2014/04/09/LACMA-Art-Technology-Lab-annouced-5-grant-recipients</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;LACMA Art + Technology Lab announced 5 grant recipients. We are delighted to be part of this initiative. Here are some press materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lacma.wordpress.com/2014/04/09/announcing-art-technology-lab-artist-grant-awards/&quot;&gt;Official announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lacma.org/sites/default/files/LACMAGrantRecipientAnnouncementRelease.pdf&quot;&gt; Press release&lt;/a&gt;
###New York Times Art Beat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/04/09/los-angeles-museum-grants-to-promote-art-and-technology/&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;architect-magazine&quot;&gt;Architect magazine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.architectmagazine.com/arts-and-culture/lacma-selects-five-recipients-for-its-inaugural-art--technology-lab-grant-awards_o.aspx&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5533/14025202525_9c58f9122b_z.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
